Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Subjects PE.029
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Subjects
1871-2017
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Filardo, Peter
Malmgreen, Gail
Bernhardt, Debra E.
Interference Archive
PE.029
41 Linear Feet in 26 record cartons, 28 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize flat boxes, 1 flat file folder, and folders in 6 shared boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Subjects (1871-2017) is an artificial collection of vertical files was accumulated gradually over the years as staff set aside ephemera that was relevant to Tamiment Library's collecting focus but did not belong in discreet collections. This collection consists of brochures, bulletins, catalogs, flyers, clippings, leaflets, manifestoes, maps, pamphlets, press releases, programs, and other printed ephemera related to subjects connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, and other movements.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical Note
The Tamiment Library, New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of printed ephemera gradually over the years through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, organizations, and bookstores, and through exchanges with other libraries via the Collectors' Network, which was organized by Russell Benedict at the University of Nevada in the 1970s and promoted through his newsletter Top Secret. Tamiment Library staff added materials to this collection on a regular basis.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Subjects (1871-2017) is composed of printed ephemera related to the primary collecting areas of the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives: Leftist politics and labor history. This collection includes files on events, places, and demographic groups that were of interest to members of the political Left in the United States. Files in this collection relate to broad topics such as organized labor, radical politics, protest movements, and political systems, and include materials on collective bargaining, Marxism, protest movements against the Vietnam War, United States elections, the Civil Rights movement, Women's Liberation, and the Iranian Revolution, for example. These subjects are documented by broadsides, brochures, bulletins, catalogs, clippings, flyers, leaflets, manifestoes, newsletters, pamphlets, press releases, reports, and other documents.
Arrangement
Collection is organized into 26 series; one for each letter of the alphabet. Files are arranged alphabetically by file title.
Series are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations PE 036
Printed Ephemera Collection of Individuals PE 030
Printed Ephemera Collection on Trade Unions PE 001
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library.
Various materials were found in the repository and added to this collection. The accession numbers associated with this material are: 2014.021, 2014.030, 2014.050, 2014.053, 2014.055, 2014.078, 2014.090, and 2019.056.
The accession numbers 2000.264, NPA.2000.339, NPA.2001.031, NPA.2001.094, NPA.2002.013, and NPA.2005.066 are also associated with this collection.
In March 2023, Interference Archive deaccessioned duplicate ephemera and publications on Occupy Wall Street from their collections and transferred these materials to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives; the accession number associated with this transfer is 2023.095.
Antinuclear movement -- United States.; Peace movements -- United States.; Communist countries; Radicalism -- United States.; Trotskyism.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements.; Student movements -- United States.; New Left -- United States.; Fliers (printed matter); Brochures.; Pamphlets.; Catalogs.; Political campaigns -- New York (State) -- New York.; Anarchism -- United States.; Gay liberation movement -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Socialism -- United States.; Feminism -- United States.; Manifestoes.; Demonstrations -- United States.; Sacco-Vanzetti Case.; Bulletins.; Leaflets (printed works); Press releases.; Printed ephemera.; Fascism.; Civil rights.; Communism.; Reports.; Anti-war demonstrations.; Filardo, Peter; Malmgreen, Gail; Bernhardt, Debra E.; Interference Archive
- A, 1904-2017; 2.25 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 2 shared boxes
  - Abortion (Pro Choice), 1976-1981 (Box 1, Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Affirmative Action, 1976, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Afghan War -- Protest Movements, 2001-2011 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - The Albany "Trial", 1920 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Alcoholism, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Almanacs, 1917 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Amandla U.S. Tour, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Anarchism and Anarchists, 1904-2015 (Box 1, Box 29, Folder 8-9)
  - Anarchism and Anarchists, 1974- (Box 1)
  - Anarchism and Anarchists, 1975- (Box 1)
  - Anarchism and Anarchists, 2003-2008 (Box 1)
  - Anarchism and Anarchists: Exhibition "Gilded Rage: Anarchy in the New America 1886-1916" Queens Borough Public Library, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Anarchism and Anarchists: Mid-Atlantic Gathering, 1993- (Box 1)
  - Anarchism and Anarchists: Providence Anarchistst Bookfair, 2005, undated (Box 1)
  - Animal Rights, undated (Box 1)
  - Angola, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement, 1965-1991 (Box 1, Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Bush Protests, 2001-2008 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Anti-Colonial Movements, 1928-1935 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Anti-Communist Movements I, 1942-1947 (Box 1, Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Anti-Communist Movements II, 1942-, undated (Box 1)
  - Anti-Communist Movements II, 1942-1982, undated (Box 1)
  - Anti-Imperialism -- Latin America, 1968-1975 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Lynching Legislation, 1921- (Box 1)
  - Anti-Military Service, Compulsory / Anti-Draft, 1935-, undated (Box 1)
  - Anti-Nixon Protests, 1968-1973 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Nuclear Movement, 1949-1987 (Box 1, Box 28, Folder 8-9, Box Shared Tamiment 171, Folder 21, Box 42, Folder 1-2)
  - Anti-Reagan Protests, circa 1980s (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Antisemitism, 1939-1987 (Box 1, Box 30, Folder 5, Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Socialism, 1912- (Box 1)
  - Anti-Trump Protests, 2017 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Union Activities, 1977-, undated (Box 1)
  - Anti-War Movements, 1915- (Box 1)
  - Appalachia, 1964- (Box 1)
  - Arabs, 1955-, undated (Box 1)
  - Arab-Americans, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Arab Spring -- Egypt, 2011 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Arbitration, 1951-1963 (Box 1)
  - Argentina, 1944-2002, undated (Box 1, Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Arm and Hammer Emblem, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Art and Artists, 1963-1986 (Box 30, Folder 10, Box Shared Tamiment 186, Folder 9)
  - Asian-Americans, 1976-1995 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic Charter (1941) (Box 1)
  - Atomic Energy, 1973- (Box 1)
  - Atomic Weapons, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Attica Prision, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Box 28, Folder 10, Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Austria, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Automation (pamphlet), 1955 (Box 1)
  - Autoworkers, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- B, 1894-2017; 4.25 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 shared box
  - Banks and Banking, 1926-1972 (Box 1, Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Berkeley, CA, 1965- (Box 1)
  - Berlin (postcards, images from 1830), undated (Box 1)
  - Bisbee (AZ) Deportations, 1917- (Box 1)
  - Black Americans -- Politics, 1935-1971 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Black Britons -- Politics, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Black Capitalism, 1970-1971 (Box 55, Folder 13, Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Black History, 1940-1968 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
  - Black History Month, 1975-2013 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Black-Jewish Solidarity, 1951-1994 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Black Liberation Movement, 1935-1975 (Box 1, Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Black Nationalism, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Black Power, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Black Separatism, 1968-1969 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Black Unity Conference, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Black-White Solidarity, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Bolshevism, 1921-1935 (Box 1, Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Booker T. Washington (Troopship), 1943 (Box 1)
  - Boston Area Political Activities I, 1970- (Box 1)
  - Boston Area Political Activities II, 1970- (Box 1)
  - Boston City Hospital, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Boston Transportation Crisis, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Boycotts / Strikes I, 1894-2017 (Box 2, Box 31, Folder 13, Box Shared Tamiment 187, Folder 4, Box 50, Folder 1-2)
  - Boycotts / Strikes II, 1947- (Box 2)
  - Boycotts: Coors, 1977-1987 (Box 2)
  - Brazil -- Indigenous Peoples, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Bread Trust, circa 1909 (Box 2)
  - Broyles Bills, 1949- (Box 2)
  - Bulgaria (People's Republic of), 1957 (Box 2)
  - Busing (Boston), 1975-1978 (Box 2, Box 31, Folder 14)
- C, 1873-2017; 4.25 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 2 shared boxes
  - Cable Street, Battle of (75th Anniversary), 2011 (Box 2)
  - Caldwell, Earl --Trial, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Calendars, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Cambodia, 1970- (Box 2)
  - Cameroon, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Camp Eureka (Catskills, NY), 1951 (Box 2)
  - Capital Punishment, 1969-2002 (Box 2, Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Capitalism, 1937-1951 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1970-1984 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons (Labor Reports), 1989, undated (Box 2)
  - Catalogs, 1968-2012 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Catonsville Nine, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Caucausus Region, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Censorship, 1954-2004 (Box 2, Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Central America, 1984- (Box 2)
  - Central Park Jogger Case, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Centralia Case (Washington State), 1919- (Box 2)
  - Chicago Conspiracy, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Chicanos, 1954-2002 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Child Labor / Child Labor Laws, 1873-1980 (Box 2)
  - Chile I, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Chile II, 1963-1974 (Box 2)
  - China, 1952-1978 (Box 2, Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Christian Radicals, 1978- (Box 2)
  - City Planning, 1969-2002 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights I, 1942-1964 (Box 2, Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Civil Rights II, 1942- (Box 2)
  - Civil Rights, undated (Box 2)
  - Civil Rights: Harlem Riots, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Civil Rights: Mississippi, 1963- (Box 2)
  - Class Struggle, 1899-2005 (Box 2, Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Cleveland Press Case, undated (Box 2)
  - Coal I, 1919-, undated (Box 2)
  - Coal II, 1919-, undated (Box 2)
  - Coal Miners, 1949, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - COINTELPRO, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Cold War, 1948-1961 (Box 2, Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Collective Bargaining, 1944-2017 (Box 2, Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Collective Bargaining, 1968-1983 (Box 2)
  - Collective Bargaining: Canada, 1966- (Box 2)
  - Communism, 1912-1963 (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
  - Community Control: New York City School System, 1970- (Box 2)
  - Comparable Worth: Equal Employment I, 1981- (Box 2)
  - Comparable Worth: Equal Employment II, 1981- (Box 2)
  - Confederacia de los Partidos Comunistas de América Latine y Caribe, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Congress on Religion and Politics, 1988 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Conscientious Objection, 1917-, undated (Box 3)
  - Convict Labor, 1925- (Box 3)
  - Cooperation and Cooperatives / Co-ops, 1920-1931 (Box 3, Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Cooperation and Cooperatives: Consumer Goods Advertisements, undated (Box 3)
  - Cooperation and Cooperatives: Great Britain, 1933- (Box 3)
  - Cooperatives: Laws (New York State), 1920- (Box 3)
  - Cork City Fire, 1920 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Corporations, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Counter Culture, 1967- (Box 3)
  - Counter-Inaugural Ball, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Credit Unions, 1940- (Box 3)
  - Cuba, 1944-1972 (Box 3, Box Shared Tamiment 171, Folder 18, Box 33, Folder 12-13, Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Cuba I, 1960- (Box 3)
  - Cuba II, 1960- (Box 3)
  - Cuba, 1973- (Box 3)
  - Cuba: Anti-Castro, undated (Box 3)
  - Cuba: Newspaper clippings, 1960- (Box 3)
  - Cuban Revolution, 1959-1994 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Curtis, Mark --Trial, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Cyprus -- Turkish Invasion, 1974 (Box Shared Tamiment 186, Folder 1)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1941-, undated (Box 3, Box 34, Folder 3)
- D, 1903-2002; 2 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 3 manuscript boxes, and 2 shared boxes
  - Dachau Concentration Camp, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Democracy, 1947-1991 (Box Shared Tamiment 186, Folder 2, Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Democratic Convention: Chicago, 1968 (Box 3, Box Shared Tamiment 171, Folder 17, Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Dies Committee on Un-American Activities, 1938- (Box 3)
  - Direct Action, 1972-1995 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Directories, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Directories: Trades (New York) in German and English, 1919, undated (Box 3)
  - Disarmament, 1913-, undated (Box 3)
  - Discrimination in Housing, 1948- (Box 3)
  - District 1: 1977 School Board Election (Box 3)
  - Divorce, 1903 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Domestic Violence, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Dominican Republic, 1965-1975 (Box 3, Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Draft Resistance I, 1918-1980 (Box 3, Box 29, Folder 15, Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Draft Resistance II, 1918, 1958- (Box 3)
  - Draft Resistance, 1980-, undated (Box 3)
  - Drake Bakery Plant Closure, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Dreyfus Affair, 1987-, undated (Box 3)
  - Drug Trafficking, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Dumbarton Oaks Conference (Creation of the United Nations), 1945 (Box 3)
- E, 1914-2016; 3.25 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 shared box
  - East Pakistan -- Indian Invasion, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Ecology, 1970-, undated (Box 3)
  - Economics, 1933-1980 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Education: Free Schools, 1971- (Box 3)
  - Education: U.S., 1964-1999 (Box 3, Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Egypt, 1957- (Box 4)
  - Eight-Hour Day, 1886-1937 (Box 4, Box 34, Folder 17)
  - El Salvador I, 1981-1987 (Box 4, Box 34, Folder 18)
  - El Salvador II, 1982- (Box 4)
  - El Salvador III, 1982- (Box 4)
  - Elections: United States, 1936-2016 (Box 4, Box 28, Folder 19, Box Shared Tamiment 187, Folder 3, Box 51, Folder 13-14)
  - Elections: United States, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Emigration and Immigration, 1927- (Box 4)
  - Energy, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Environmentalism, 1970-2002 (Box Shared Tamiment 186, Folder 3, Box 34, Folder 20, Box 35, Folder 1-3)
  - Equal Pay for Equal Work, 1933- (Box 4)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1963-1976 (Box 4, Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Eritrea, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Erlich-Alter Trial, 1942-1967 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Esperanto (publications in), 1917-1971 (Box 4)
  - Espionage Act cases, 1919 (Box 4)
  - Ethiopia, 1935-1985 (Box 4, Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Etiquette Books, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Europe: War, 1915- (Box 4)
  - European War: Reparations, undated (Box 4)
  - European War: Socialism, 1914- (Box 4)
  - European War: Socialists, 1914- (Box 4)
  - Evanston, Illinois Nazi Rally, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 10)
- F, 1908-2014; 3.25 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 oversize flat box
  - Fair Employment Practices Commission, 1945- (Box 4)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1919- (Box 4)
  - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1939- (Box 4)
  - Falkland War, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Farms and Farming, 1959- (Box 4)
  - Farmworkers Movement, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Farm Workers, 1917-1979 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Fascism, 1934-1968 (Box 4, Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Fast Food Workers, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Feminism, 1914, 1975-1994, undated (Box 4, Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Ferguson, Missouri Protests, 2014 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Fifth Column (AmericanYouth Congress), undated (Box 4)
  - Finland, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Films, 1977-2014 (Box 4, Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Forced Labor (U.S.; Soviet Work Camps), 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - Ford Hunger March Massacre (River Rouge Plant), 1932, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Relations, 1908-1966 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Fort Dix (N.J.), 1969 (Box 4)
  - Forty Hour Week, undated (Box 4)
  - Fraina, Louis C. -- Trial, 1920 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - France, 1941-1976 (Box 4, Box 36, Folder 6)
  - France -- General Strike, 1966-1968 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Francoist Spain, 1945-1964 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Free Schools, Director of (US), 1970 (Box 4)
  - Free Speech, undated (Box 4)
  - Free Trade Area of the Americas (FTAA), 2000-2002 (Box 5, Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Freedom Budget, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1979- (Box 5)
  - Freedom of the Press, 1960- (Box 5)
  - Fruit Trade, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Full Employment Policies, 1945, undated (Box 5, Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Futurism, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 10)
- G, 1909-2007; 2.25 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 3 manuscript boxes
  - Games, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Garment Workers, 1929-1965 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Gay Rights, 1975-2003 (Box 5, Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Ghana, 1965-1972 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - G.I. Movement: Europe, 1967, undated (Box 5)
  - G.I. Movement: U.S. I, 1968, undated (Box 5)
  - G.I. Movement: U.S. II, 1968, undated (Box 5)
  - Germany, 1921-1962 (Box 5, Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Germany, undated (Box 5)
  - Germany: National Defense, 1950- (Box 5)
  - Germany: Socialism, 1945- (Box 5)
  - Germany: Trade Union Movement, 1925, undated (Box 5)
  - Global Warming, 2007- (Box 5)
  - Globalization, 1967-2001 (Box 5, Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Goldwaterism, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Gori, Pietro -- Defamation Trial, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Grand Jury Investigations, 1970- (Box 5)
  - Graphic Arts Industries, 1933 (Box 5)
  - Great Britain, 1938- (Box 5)
  - Greece, 1968- (Box 5)
  - Green Party, 1990- (Box 5)
  - Greenwich Village (NYC): Map and Guide, 1928 (Box 5)
  - Grenada, 1983 (Box 5, Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Guaranteed Employment and Wage Plans, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Guatemala, 1953- (Box 5)
  - Guerrillas, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Guidelines, 1954-1970 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Guyana, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 8)
- H, 1915-2004; 2.75 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 2 shared boxes
  - Haiti, 1991- (Box 5)
  - Hammond, Indiana Massacre (Standard Car Company), undated (Box 5)
  - Harlem (New York, N.Y.), 1935-1968 (Box 5, Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Harlem Six, 1971-1975 (Box 5, Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Harrisburg Seven, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Hawks Nest Tunnel (W. Va.) 1930 I, 1981- (Box 5)
  - Hawks Nest Tunnel (W. Va.) 1930 II, 1981- (Box 5)
  - Haymarket Square Riots, Chicago, 1886, 1936-1986 (Box 5, Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Health and Welfare Benefits Survey - Unions, undated (Box 5)
  - Health Insurance, 1915-, undated (Box 5)
  - Health Insurance Plans, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Health Services, 1949-1994 (Box 6, Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Health Services: Women, 1970- (Box 6)
  - Hiroshima, 1962- (Box 6)
  - Historical Materialism, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - History of the Left, 2002 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Hollywood Ten, 1950- (Box 6)
  - Home Health Workers, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Hospital Workers, 1968- (Box 6)
  - Hospitality Workers, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Household Workers, 1973- (Box 6)
  - Housing, 1935-2004 (Box 6, Box Shared Tamiment 186, Folder 4, Box Shared Tamiment 171, Folder 19, Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Housing, 1947- (Box 6)
  - Housing, 1960- (Box 6)
  - Housing: New York City, 1968-, undated (Box 6)
  - Housing: New York City I, 1970- (Box 6)
  - Housing: New York City II, 1970- (Box 6)
  - Housing Authorities, 1945, undated (Box 6)
  - Housing: Interracial, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Humor, undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Hunger Strikes, 1928 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Hungarian Revolution, 1956 (Box 6, Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Hungary, 1949-1959 (Box 6)
  - Hydrogen Bomb, 1950- (Box 6)
- I, 1913-2006; 3.25 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 oversize flat box
  - Immigrants and Immigration, 1943-2003 (Box 6, Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Impeachment: Nixon, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Imperialism, 1964-1972 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
  - Incentives in Industry, 1943- (Box 6)
  - Individualism, 1940 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Indochina, 1950- (Box 6)
  - Indonesia, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Industrial Accidents, 1913- (Box 6)
  - Insurance: Social Security, 1936- (Box 6)
  - Insurance: Unemployment, 1934- (Box 6)
  - Insurance: Unemployment - Maritime Industry, 1943, undated (Box 6)
  - Integration, 1926-2003 (Box 6, Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Integration: Regional (United States), 1960- (Box 6)
  - Internal Security Act of 1950 / McCarran Act, 1950-1963 (Box 6, Box 38, Folder 6)
  - International Women's Day, 1974-2003, undated (Box 6)
  - International Women's Year, 1975-1977 (Box 6)
  - Iran, 1973-1986 (Box 6, Box 28, Folder 3, Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Iran-Iraq War, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Iran-Contra, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Iraq, 1959-2005 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Iraq War - Anti (Spanish language): Barcelona?, 2002- (Box 6)
  - Iraq War, 2003: Protest Movements, 2002-2006 (Box 6, Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Israel, 1953- (Box 7)
  - Israel-Arab War, 1948-1949, 2003-2006 (Box 7, Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Italian Americans, 1928-1969 (Box 7, Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Italy, 1944- (Box 7)
- J, 1927-2000; 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 manuscript box
  - Jackson (Miss.) / Jackson Daily News, 1965- (Box 7)
  - Japan, 1927- (Box 7)
  - Japanese Peace Conference, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Jesuits / Freemasons, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish Radical Activism (includes Jewish Liberation Service Bulletins), 1971- (Box 7)
  - Jewish People, 1940-1986 (Box 7, Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Jewish People: Clothing Industry, 1991, undated (Box 7)
  - Jewish People in Russia, 1949- (Box 7)
  - Jim Crow Laws, 1940-1962 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Jobs for Youth March, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Journalism, 1967-2000 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - July 4th, undated (Box 7)
- K, 1919-1970s; 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 manuscript bo
  - Kansas City Four, 1922 (Box 7)
  - Katanga (Congo), 1961-1965 (Box 7, Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy, John F. -- Assassination, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - King, Martin Luther Jr. -- Assassination, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Korea, 1950- (Box 7)
  - Korean War, 1950- (Box 7)
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1919-1970s, undated (Box 7)
  - Kurds, 1963 (Box 7)
- L, 1878-2018; 2.5 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons and 3 manuscript boxes
  - Labor - Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Box 7)
  - Labor and Laboring classes: Addresses, speeches, etc., 1975 (Box 7)
  - Labor and Laboring classes: Anti-war attitudes, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Labor and Laboring classes: Folklore, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Labor and Laboring classes: General Items, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Labor and Laboring classes: Negroes, 1948- (Box 7)
  - Labor and Laboring classes: Television, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Labor and Trade Relations-U.S./Japan, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
  - Labor Day, 1956-2018 (Box 7, Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Labor Day Stamp, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Labor Education Extension, 1947- (Box 7)
  - Labor Graphics, 1989-, undated (Box 7)
  - Labor Injunctions, 1931- (Box 7)
  - Labor Laws and Legislation, 1959- (Box 7)
  - Labor Management, 1930- (Box 7)